<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sainth.de</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/</link><description>Recent content on sainth.de</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>©2015-2020 Tobias Wink</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 19:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.sainth.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About me</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sainth.de/about/</guid><description>Hello, I don&amp;rsquo;t like to talk about myself. Nevertheless, every visitor should get the possibility to get an approximate picture about me, my experiences and my know-how, so that maybe my choice of topics, opinions and other statements can be better understood.
I was born in the 1980s as part of a large family and grew up in a small town in East Westphalia (Germany). Besides the disadvantages of having older siblings, it also had advantages.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/privacy_policy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sainth.de/privacy_policy/</guid><description>Personal data (usually referred to just as &amp;ldquo;data&amp;rdquo; below) will only be processed by us to the extent necessary and for the purpose of providing a functional and user-friendly website, including its contents, and the services offered there.
Per Art. 4 No. 1 of Regulation (EU) 2016/679, i.e. the General Data Protection Regulation (hereinafter referred to as the &amp;ldquo;GDPR&amp;rdquo;), &amp;ldquo;processing&amp;rdquo; refers to any operation or set of operations such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation, alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination, or otherwise making available, alignment, or combination, restriction, erasure, or destruction performed on personal data, whether by automated means or not.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/projects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sainth.de/projects/</guid><description>pgTune arose from a project work during my master studies. With the help of a simple form it is possible to generate optimized parameters for the configuration of a PostgreSQL server. It is a fork of pgtune and offers a slightly different user interface and especially a REST API. This means that this version of pgTune can also be used, for example, for the automatic deployment of VMs and/or containers.</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/publications/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sainth.de/publications/</guid><description> Masterthesis [EN]: A decentralized communication approach for federated learning Term paper [DE]: Attacks on SSL 3.0 and TLS 1.0 using CBC mode and predecessor versions of these attacks Bachelorthesis [DE]: Generation of the persistence layer by creating a domain-specific language</description></item><item><title>JWTs, a supplement to BasicAuth</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/blog/jwts-and-basic-auth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 19:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.sainth.de/blog/jwts-and-basic-auth/</guid><description>&lt;p>Most REST APIs support BasicAuth when they require authentication and manage user data themselves. When choosing the function to protect stored passwords, it is important to find the right balance between user convenience and attacker protection. On the one hand, you want to keep adversaries at bay for as long as possible, but on the other hand, you also want to give users the shortest possible response times. All adaptive password hashing methods recommended by &lt;a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Password_Storage_Cheat_Sheet#Impose_infeasible_verification_on_attacker">OWASP&lt;/a> therefore offer the option of configuring the speed of the algorithm via a &lt;em>work factor&lt;/em>. In order to be able to select this &lt;em>work factor&lt;/em> as high as possible, without annoying the users unnecessarily, the use of JWTs lends itself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nexus as a binary repository for APKs</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/blog/use-nexus-as-a-binary-repository-for-apks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 21:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.sainth.de/blog/use-nexus-as-a-binary-repository-for-apks/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you use &lt;a href="https://www.sonatype.com/download-oss-sonatype">Nexus OSS&lt;/a> to store your finished binary artifacts, you will of course want to do the same for your APKs. Since I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on an Android app professionally, I&amp;rsquo;ve now had the chance to gain my experience with it. Because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to make the same pitfalls again next time, I will explain it here step by step.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My previous experiences with &lt;a href="https://gradle.org/">Gradle&lt;/a> are (fortunately) hardly worth mentioning, so first an extensive Google research was on the agenda. This soon led me to the &lt;a href="https://docs.gradle.org/current/userguide/maven_plugin.html">Maven plugin&lt;/a> for Gradle and the following configuration for &lt;code>uploadArchives&lt;/code>:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-groovy" data-lang="groovy">apply plugin: &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;maven&amp;#39;&lt;/span>
uploadArchives &lt;span style="color:#f92672">{&lt;/span>
repositories &lt;span style="color:#f92672">{&lt;/span>
mavenDeployer &lt;span style="color:#f92672">{&lt;/span>
repository&lt;span style="color:#f92672">(&lt;/span>url: &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;file://localhost/tmp/myRepo/&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">)&lt;/span>
&lt;span style="color:#f92672">}&lt;/span>
&lt;span style="color:#f92672">}&lt;/span>
&lt;span style="color:#f92672">}&lt;/span>
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>A corresponding call with &lt;code>gradlew clean assemble uploadArchives&lt;/code> ran successfully, but no artifacts were stored. So I then became aware of the Gradle user guide &lt;a href="https://docs.gradle.org/current/userguide/artifact_management.html">Publishing artifacts&lt;/a> and realized that the APKs must be declared so that &lt;code>uploadArchives&lt;/code> also knows what is to be uploaded.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Asciidoctor PDF</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/blog/asciidoctor-pdf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 14:15:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.sainth.de/blog/asciidoctor-pdf/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the meantime, a company I know has noticed that it has also encountered the problem described &lt;a href="https://www.sainth.de/blog/word-is-too-complex/">here&lt;/a>. After all, any kid can use Word, right? As much as I would love to utter sentences like &amp;ldquo;I told you so.&amp;rdquo; in these moments, I also like to offer my help in such situations. For this reason, one of the documents that are regularly updated and versioned and made available to third parties will now be switched to AsciiDoc as a test. At the same time &lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/">git&lt;/a> will be introduced for change tracking and versioning, but that&amp;rsquo;s another challenge I might write about some other time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A different thinking approach</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/blog/a-different-thinking-approach/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 20:15:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.sainth.de/blog/a-different-thinking-approach/</guid><description>&lt;p>Unfortunately, some time has passed again since the last post. In the &lt;a href="https://www.sainth.de/blog/brief-history-of-functional-programming/">last post&lt;/a> I wrote something about the history of functional and imperative programming. This one is now to deal with the, compared to imperative programming, different way of thinking. The source code examples shown here are based on Java for the imperative examples and Haskell for the functional examples. I will try to use only functions available in the language standard and not library functions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In imperative programming, one describes in detail the steps that must be performed by the computer to accomplish the task. In contrast, functional programming does not describe &lt;em>HOW&lt;/em> something is to be computed, but &lt;em>WHAT&lt;/em>. Not for nothing functional programming languages belong to the declarative programming languages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By the functions, just as in mathematics, the &amp;ldquo;world&amp;rdquo; is represented or defined in the actual state. In general, functional programming with its terminology and concepts is very strongly based on mathematics, which makes it not easy for not math affine humans. If one managed to understand the concepts the large advantage is that one can rely on the mathematical background of these concepts. Thus, the correctness of a program can then be proven with &amp;ldquo;relatively&amp;rdquo; little effort, at least compared to imperative programs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A brief history of functional programming</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/blog/brief-history-of-functional-programming/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 18:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.sainth.de/blog/brief-history-of-functional-programming/</guid><description>&lt;p>Functional programming is on everyone&amp;rsquo;s lips and concepts from functional programming are being adopted everywhere in imperative languages. At the moment I am also taking a closer look at these concepts and would like to publish my findings here in the form of a series of articles. But let&amp;rsquo;s start with a short historical review.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have to admit that the more I researched the story, the more fascinating I found it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Word &amp; Co have too many disadvantages</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/blog/word-is-too-complex/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 15:20:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.sainth.de/blog/word-is-too-complex/</guid><description>&lt;p>I would like to dedicate this post to my little sister and all the others who think they have to write term papers, theses etc. with Word and are not able to integrate page numbers, tables of contents or other necessities. The bottom line is that such papers are really just about creating a PDF with the desired content to either submit digitally or print out.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="whats-wrong-with-wysiwyg-word-processors">What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with WYSIWYG word processors?&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>They offer too many possibilities to use them incorrectly. It already starts with the fact that you can format a paragraph independently of its style sheet. If you are not careful enough it results in uncontrolled growth. I saw documents where the author was surprised that the generation of the table of contents did not work. The cause was quickly found when looking at the structure of the document. There were no headings for the program, because instead of the correct style sheet, the designated headings were formatted manually. So for the human eye, the headings were there, but all the supposed headings had the Paragraph style.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Versioning or change tracking is complicated and many have never heard of it. In addition, it is cumbersome to work with several people on a single document, because the different versions of a document must first be merged back into one document.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>The Phoenix Project</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/blog/the-phoenix-project/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.sainth.de/blog/the-phoenix-project/</guid><description>&lt;p>I never thought I would actually read a book that is both a technical book and a novel, that would really excite me enough to want to write a review about it. But this hardly imaginable situation has now occurred. First of all, I would like to state that I was not promised any benefits for this post and that I purchased the book quite regularly in a store. It is the book &lt;em>The Phoenix Project - A Novel About IT, DevOps, and Helping Your Business Win&lt;/em> by Gene Kim, Kevin Behr, and George Spafford.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Phoenix Project inimitably tells the story of Bill Palmer, a midrange computer department manager at Parts Unlimited, an auto parts manufacturer. Parts Unlimited&amp;rsquo;s market situation is very tight, with competitors always one step ahead. Bill&amp;rsquo;s survival tactic has always been to fly under the radar and not stand out. So the day comes when Bill, running late for work, is called into her office by the HR manager on his way to work. Once there, he learns that his boss and his boss&amp;rsquo;s boss, the CIO, are no longer with the company and that he is now to become the head of IT operations and that this choice was made by the CEO himself. Bill firmly intends to refuse the promotion, but somehow the charismatic CEO Steve Masters manages to run him over in conversation so that he does not manage to refuse the promotion.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>