<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sainth.de</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/</link><description>Recent content on sainth.de</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>©2015-2020 Tobias Wink</copyright><atom:link href="https://www.sainth.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About me</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sainth.de/about/</guid><description>Hello, I don&amp;rsquo;t like to talk about myself. Nevertheless, every visitor should get the possibility to get an approximate picture about me, my experiences and my know-how, so that maybe my choice of topics, opinions and other statements can be better understood.
I was born in the 1980s as part of a large family and grew up in a small town in East Westphalia (Germany). Besides the disadvantages of having older siblings, it also had advantages.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/privacy_policy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sainth.de/privacy_policy/</guid><description>Personal data (usually referred to just as &amp;ldquo;data&amp;rdquo; below) will only be processed by us to the extent necessary and for the purpose of providing a functional and user-friendly website, including its contents, and the services offered there.
Per Art. 4 No. 1 of Regulation (EU) 2016/679, i.e. the General Data Protection Regulation (hereinafter referred to as the &amp;ldquo;GDPR&amp;rdquo;), &amp;ldquo;processing&amp;rdquo; refers to any operation or set of operations such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation, alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination, or otherwise making available, alignment, or combination, restriction, erasure, or destruction performed on personal data, whether by automated means or not.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/projects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sainth.de/projects/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/publications/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sainth.de/publications/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>