<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>no-wysiwyg on sainth.de</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/tags/no-wysiwyg/</link><description>Recent content in no-wysiwyg on sainth.de</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>©2015-2020 Tobias Wink</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 15:20:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.sainth.de/tags/no-wysiwyg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Word &amp; Co have too many disadvantages</title><link>https://www.sainth.de/blog/word-is-too-complex/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 15:20:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.sainth.de/blog/word-is-too-complex/</guid><description>&lt;p>I would like to dedicate this post to my little sister and all the others who think they have to write term papers, theses etc. with Word and are not able to integrate page numbers, tables of contents or other necessities. The bottom line is that such papers are really just about creating a PDF with the desired content to either submit digitally or print out.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="whats-wrong-with-wysiwyg-word-processors">What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with WYSIWYG word processors?&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>They offer too many possibilities to use them incorrectly. It already starts with the fact that you can format a paragraph independently of its style sheet. If you are not careful enough it results in uncontrolled growth. I saw documents where the author was surprised that the generation of the table of contents did not work. The cause was quickly found when looking at the structure of the document. There were no headings for the program, because instead of the correct style sheet, the designated headings were formatted manually. So for the human eye, the headings were there, but all the supposed headings had the Paragraph style.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Versioning or change tracking is complicated and many have never heard of it. In addition, it is cumbersome to work with several people on a single document, because the different versions of a document must first be merged back into one document.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>